Contact

tuannvm@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/tuannvm (LinkedIn) tuannvm.com/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Linux

Docker

Kubernetes

Languages

Vietnamese (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

Certifications

IELTS (International English Language Testing System)

Google Cloud Certified Professional Cloud Architect

Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)

Tommy Nguyen

Kubernetes & Cloud Professional

Singapore

Summary

Being a cloud-focused engineer helps me work closely with development teams and keep in touch with daily operation tasks at the same time. System architecture & continuous deployment are some of my favorite topics. For over 5+ years, I've worked with a handful of infrastructures including bare metal, cloud computing, micro-services,.... By experiencing those systems, I've earned appropriate skills & expertise to deal with a variety of demands from customer. In addition, being familiar with latest technology & toolset is by far my strongest point due to consistent involvement on the recent projects. And last but definitely not least, I am considered as a diligent, fast-learning, right on time person.

Experience

Vungle

Senior Site Reliability Engineer September 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Singapore

90 Seconds

Senior DevOps Engineer January 2019 - September 2019 (9 months)

Singapore

- Optimise & refactor CI/CD pipeline, add automated steps required by specific workloads
- Utilise Google Cloud Platform services to handle sophisticated business requirements
- Embrace infrastructure-as-code philosophy, use Terraform & Ansible to spin up team resources
- Work closely with Data team, collaborate on Data pipeline & workflow
- Make use of GKE (Google Kubernetes Engine) for many kind of workload

honestbee DevOps Engineer July 2017 - January 2019 (1 year 7 months) Singapore

- Maintained & Operated a system which serve 500k+ customers across 6 countries.
- Successfully migrated backend application from a legacy platform to Kubernetes.
- Was being an active contributor for Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF)
- Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA) & Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD)
- Implemented centralized secret management for kubernetes clusters using vault.
- Integrated OpenID access management with kubnernetes, which allow developers using cooperated account to gain access to cluster.
- Developed a framework based on kops to allow cluster creation with just a few steps.
- Wrote several tools for internal usage & cluster management.

ClickMedix

DevOps Lead

July 2016 - June 2017 (1 year)

- Be responsible for an E-healthcare system which serve 100+ hospital across the world.
- Migrated from a manual deployment workflow to fully-automated CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins.
- Optimized resource usage, thus greatly reduce operation cost.

Cogini

System Manager

February 2016 - July 2016 (6 months)

Ho Chi Minh City

- Mainly focused on cloud computing (Amazon web services, Google cloud platform).
- Supported multiple outsourcing projects.
- Planned and implement automatic deployment service, apply to production systems
- Got familiar with CI/CD process.
- Ensured services comply to predefined SLA.
- Monitored system metrics & stats 24/7.
- Make sure customer's servers comply to all security rules & polices.

Haravan

Senior System & Network Engineer July 2014 - February 2016 (1 year 8 months)

Ho Chi Minh City

- Deployed System, Network Infrastructure for a newly-formed startup.
- Utilized open source softwares (MongoDB, ElasticSearch, Nginx, Ansible...)
- Setup tools to monitor & handle attack from outside (DDOS, Flood, Injection...)
- Implemented 2-step authentication on Windows, Unix, Web.
- Integrate LDAP with internal services.
- Migrate part of the current running system to Azure for saving cost.
- Get familiar with AWS services.
- Monitoring infrastructure with various tools, including: PRTG, Statsd & Graphite, Splunk, own-developed tools...
- Spent a lot of time with Haproxy, Dnsmasq, Dns-unblocking technique.
- Wrote several admin tools using Node.js, shellscript...
- Began to focus more on microservices (Docker, CoreOS...), steadily "dockerize" services and deploy them to production.

Công Ty Cổ Phần Giải Trí Di Động (ME Corp) System & Network Engineer April 2013 - July 2014 (1 year 4 months) Ho Chi Minh City

- Rebuilt appstore system.
- Scan security for newly-deployed services.
- Built download system, which serve 1000+ concurent connection.
- Wrote several scripts for automation.
- Setup & configured access point, modem, router, switch...
- Deployed "Wifi advertising platform" which covered 100+ coffee shops.
- Implemented open source log system (up to millions record per day) using ELK stack.
- Configured HA & load balancing environment (MySQL master slave, HA Proxy, LVS)
- Setup CSM (centralized server management) which handle daily basis tasks with a friendly UI.

FPT Telecom
System Specialist
January 2011 - March 2013 (2 years 3 months)
Ho Chi Minh City

- Deployed Citrix XenApp and XenDesktop for 30+ users.
- Configured web server using lighttpd with PHP fastcgi and squid caching system for websites, forums
- Deployed & Operated serveral online games, work a lot with PXE, cygwin in these projects.
- Built email marketing system which supported sending ~200k emails / day.
- Setup email servers for sendo.vn (e-commerce website) and senpay.vn (online payment).
- Maintained & updated FPT Online dns system.
- Deployed centralize source code management (SVN) used by companywide.
- Be part of the "Content Delivery Network" taskforce, which deploy CDN system for https://e.vnxpress.net, a top news websites in Vietnam.
- Built custom linux kernel torun OS entirely on RAM.
- Write a lot of shell script to control & maintain servers.
- Built ticket tracking system using OTRS software.
- Centralized log management with graylog2, logstash and elasticsearch.

Education

University of Science Ho Chi Minh City
Bachelor's Degree, Electrical, Electronic and Communications Engineering
Technology/Technician · (2006 - 2011)